Good morning and greetings to
all ladies and gentlemen. May we all always be
healthy under the protection of God. We from the
DPLK Manulif Indonesia team would like to
provide a little information about two
superior products from the
Manulife financial institution pension fund, namely the
first post-employment compensation fund DKPK program
and the second is the
PPIP program, a defined contribution pension program.
Our service in Indonesia has been in Indonesia for 29
years and our position in the industry
is the largest joint venture company
in Indonesia with managed funds of Rp24.3
trillion. There are two employee welfare systems in
Indonesia, there are mandatory programs
and there are voluntary programs. The
mandatory program is the BPJS national social security system
and also for the
Job Creation Law number 11 of 2020 in accordance
with PP Number 35 of 2001, PPJS and the
Job Creation Law
each stand alone and do not
replace each other while DPLK
in accordance with Law Number 11
of 92 DPLK is to reduce the
offset in the obligations in Law Number 11 of
2020, namely to regulate the payment of
severance pay for service awards and compensation money for
tax facility rights in the first DPLK program,
company contributions can
reduce taxes.  Article 25 corporate income tax is then
charged to Tan without fiscal correction,
while secondly, employee contributions
can reduce the
current year's PPH 21 income tax and thirdly,
investment returns are not subject to tax and
finally, the final and final tax on
pension benefits, namely 0 to 50 million, is
0 and above R million is 5%.
How is the example of
corporate taxation? We give an example of the
company's profit of 20 billion and the
severance pension reserve of 55 billion.
What is the difference between being reserved through DPLK
Manulif or being reserved independently?
If it is reserved independently, the
gross profit of 20 billion pays BPH Article 25 tax
of 22%, which is 4.4 billion, then it is deducted
from the severance pension reserve so the net profit is
10,600 million. Meanwhile, if it is reserved
through DPLK Manulif, the gross profit of 20
billion is deducted 5 billion first
as a pension reserve. So, the amount
subject to PPh Article 25 of 22% is
15 billion, which is 3.3 billion, so the
net profit becomes
11,700 million. The difference in net profit
is
1,100 million. Meanwhile, the benefits for
tax employees on their pension benefits,
for example, Mr. A's pension benefit
is 2 billion, then the payment through the
tax company for his benefits is
437,500,000, then the pension fund
taken home is
1,562,500,000, while  If the
pension fund is provided through DPLK,
the tax on the benefits is
Rp97,500,000, so the pension fund
taken home is 1
million,
900,250,000, the difference is Rp340
million. While the mechanism of the DPLK
PPIP program, the contributions given are
directly placed in the names that
have been determined by the company, the
investment results are not taxed
and there are five investment options and the
benefit payments are for
normal retirement, accelerated retirement, minimum age
50 years, death retirement and
disability pension benefits. While the
mechanism in the DPLK program at the KPK,
the company's contributions will be placed in the
company's account in installments, the
investment results and benefit payments are the same
and paid all at once
directly to the employee's account. Well, ladies and
gentlemen, to get a
detailed presentation, please contact
Ejen Andalan Jakarta Power to
get an appointment and we will
give the presentation online
or onsite. Thank you and see
you later.